Dany Ventura

Los Angeles, California, United States



danyv235@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/dany-ventura-1099a570

Summary

I strongly believe that my "soft" skills are my finest skills.

Since my early adulthood, I've been engaging with people in many different ways.

One of my first jobs that I had was a sales rep. for very famous nutrition company. I was always told I'm a "People's Man", from then just flourished as I grew older.

I connect quite fast with pretty much anyone and make the other person feel comfortable, I frequently heard - "It's feels like I've known you for years"

My natural way of connecting with new people was first and foremost a BIG smile. I tend to find genuine interest in any new person a meet, always try to lighten the mood with a small joke or a funny story.

In addition I'm good listener, I understood that principal very early that almost anyone loves to talk about themselves if you are sincerely show interest.

My work experience ranges from Sales in various industries, I speak 3 languages (English, Spanish, Hebrew and a tad of Portuguese).

Thank you for reading my story, and If you want to know me better - I'm a message away; -)

Experience



Sales Executive

Jole Trade Inc.

Jan 2017 - Jan 2021 (4 years 1 month)

Customer acquisition, retention, and growth strategy for a small business exclusively distributing Mon Platin products in the state of Florida:

Acquired 65 new accounts yearly

Account retention of 98.5%

Grew revenue by 35% Year Over Year

Administered e-Commerce website and responded to inbound sales requests

Supported local summit and conventions events to generate brand awareness



Owner and General Manager

SMART ECO AIR INC.

Jan 2013 - Oct 2016 (3 years 10 months)

Funded a small business employing 5 people in the Los Angeles County area, primarily focused on residential HVAC services

Exclusive vendor for American Standard HVAC systems

New sales of \$375,000 per year

Service contracts worth \$75,000 per year

Developed and implemented outbound marketing strategy

Sales Manager

TOP AC

Apr 2011 - Dec 2012 (1 year 9 months)

Responsible for service HVAC sales in the Los Angeles Country area

Acquisition of residential HVAC service contracts

Development, nurturing, and retention of customer relationship - attained 98% account retention

Grew service revenue 49% year over year

Education



The College of Management Academic Studies

College Degree in Business Administration

Licenses & Certifications

The Complete Web Developer in 2022: Zero to Mastery - Udemy UC-447413cc-2c99-42d3-9b0a-4f02fa543aae

Build Responsive Real-World Websites with HTML and CSS - Udemy UC-c1327e5b-1da4-4478-ae1f-664058b51754

Skills

Public Relations • Customer Service • Staff Development • Market Research • Promotional • Marketing • Operations • Management